NEN
[narrator] Nen abilities fall into
the following six distinct categories:
Enhances are able to strengthen
and reinforce
the natural properties
of any object they encounter.
Transmuters can manipulate
and change the quality of aura at will.
CONJURER
Similar to Transmuters Conjurers
have the ability
to materialize an object out of aura.
Emitters can propel their aura
shooting or projecting it forward.
Manipulators can use their aura
to control objects or living things.
Specialists possess rare abilities
which do not fit
within the other five categories.
One must determine
which category their aura falls into.
This is the first step
to becoming a skilled Nen user.
[theme song paying]
[Gon] Aunt Mito!
So long!
I’m gonna go find Ging, I promise!
And after I meet him,
I’m gonna come back to the island, okay?
Bye! take care! I’ll miss you!
WISH x AND x PROMISE
[narrator] Meanwhile as Gon and Killua
depart from Whale Island,
Kurapika is preparing
to begin a journey of his own.
[Kurapika] So you remember me?
[Rei] Well, yeah.
We don’t get many visitors here.
In fact, ever since you were here last,
there’s only been one other person.
This place is a whole lot harder to find
than you think.
You found this agency on your own
and that tells me you’re pretty sharp.
Even so…
I can’t introduce you
to our valued clients.
And it’s not because of your
total lack of experience.
Some of our clients
don’t seem to mind that.
The thing is
experience isn’t all you lack.
But what do you mean?
Like I told you,
I already have a Hunter’s License.
[Rei] Maybe.
But your Exam isn’t over yet.
It’s obvious.
Excuse me?
You can’t see anything, can you?
[Kurapika] Huh?
You come back when you can...
[tense breath]
[electricity buzzes]
[Mizuken] You can’t see it,
but you can sense it, huh?
Why did you do that?
[Mizuken] This?
Oh. [chuckles] I was just playing around.
-[thunder]
-This must be fate,
us crossing paths. Y’think?
Try to think of this as...
a little bit of friendly advice
from a senior.
You didn’t notice when I stole this,
or when I walked right past you, either.
You’re totally clueless.
Bastard!
Give me back my license right now!
Does a newbie who knows nothing of Nen
have a chance of beating me?
Nen, huh?
[smirks]
[thunder]
[Mizuken] Wanna give it a try?
[Kurapika panting]
Do you get it now?
There’s something important
you still lack.
Come with me.
I’ll teach you.
The real Exam has just begun.
[birds chirping]
[Mizuken] Today...
we’re going to determine
which category your aura falls under.
[focusing exhale]
There’s something forming in the water.
So, you’re a Conjurer. It’s clear.
A Conjurer…
A type whose specialty
is manifesting their aura.
I see.
I was hoping I would be an Enhancer.
Unfortunately, you can’t change
what you’re born with.
But it isn’t hopeless.
You can still learn
Enhancement techniques.
And that would make an excellent topic
for us to go over today.
Now let’s say you have the aptitude
to achieve 100 percent
mastery of Conjuration abilities.
At the most this is how much
you could master the others.
HATSU - Enhancement 60%, Transmutation 80%
Conjuration 100%, Emission 40% ...
It doesn’t matter
how fast of a learner you are,
you can never completely
master a different category.
The further a category is from your own,
the less you acquire.
Why is Specialist at zero?
Specialist is a unique category.
And their abilities aren’t the kind
you can simply teach yourself.
They’re very distinct abilities,
either inherited or acquired naturally,
a product of your environment.
So why this position?
Because the adjacent categories,
Conjurer and Manipulator,
have the greatest chance
of becoming Specialists later on.
In that respect, you still have a chance…
in a way.
Do you…
remember what you said?
[tired panting]
[Kurapika] I...
I need...
I need enough power to fight on my own!
[Mizuken] You might assume
that the fastest means to your goal
would be through Enhancement abilities…
and you’d be right.
Enhancers are able to reinforce offense,
defense and healing most efficiently.
But since you’re a Conjurer,
you can only learn Enhancer abilities
up to half potency.
If you try to exceed your limits,
it will cause you incredible strain
and that can weaken you.
It could even be fatal.
Consistent power
is the only way to stay on top.
If I were consistent in my abilities
as a Conjurer,
do you think that
it would that help me in a battle,
if I were pitted
against a Master Enhancer?
[Mizuken] Hmm...
In short, it would be difficult.
When closely compared to an Enhancer’s
offense and defense,
far more often than not
Conjurers are simply
not as evenly balanced.
But that said,
you could actually be quite formidable,
if you find your groove.
Here’s a quiz…
Can you conjure a sword
that’s able to cut through anything?
You can’t.
[Mizuken] Why not?
Because it exceeds
the bounds of human capacity.
That’s exactly right.
There are things you can never conjure,
even with 100 percent mastery.
Of course,
you could conjure a sword
that’s very sharp and sturdy.
But it would make a lot more sense
to just go out and buy one.
You wouldn’t need extra training.
You can make the sword
appear and disappear using Nen.
But conjured weapons
just aren’t as effective.
The physical versions are better.
Unfortunately,
you can’t conjure anything
that’s supernatural.
So, consider it carefully
and choose what you wish to conjure.
No mistakes allowed.
Conjuring something at will
takes a lot of concentration,
not to mention training and time.
And that’s just what it takes
for one thing.
[Rei] What a surprise…
[Kurapika] Huh?
I don’t know many people
who learned Nen in only six months.
So. What kind of employer do you want?
I’ll tell you something interesting
about spiders…
Meet me in Yorknew City on September 1st.
I would prefer to find an employer
with strong ties to the Yorknew Auction.
The job is irrelevant.
[Rei] The Yorknew City auction…
The employers who have a lot of influence,
generally post the difficult jobs.
I doubt they’re looking to hire a Hunter
with zero experience.
I see three.
Three employers who’ll decide
based on the interview
and not on your record.
And it looks like all three
are looking for bodyguards.
I’ll read, you choose, ‘k?
The first is a handgun buff.
He’s after the Misette Limited Edition
Bull Snake Model S55,
number 001.
The second is a collector of fine china.
This one is seeking Rodo Memorial Plates
from 1655 to 1657.
And the third…
is a flesh collector...
Seeking a hide with a full body tattoo
of a rising dragon,
the head of a child with Jelly Syndrome
and a few others.
That sure is quite a hobby.
All right. Take your pick.
Huh?
[Mizuken] Chains?
[Kurapika]
Yes. When you said I was a Conjurer,
that was the first thing
that came to mind.
Interesting.
But why chains?
It’s because there are some people
at large in the world right now,
who need to be chained to hell.
Oh, is that so?
Because I can’t shake
the nagging suspicion
that you’re the one
who’ll be chained down.
[Kurapika] What the hell do you know?
Wait a second! Where are you going?
I’m your teacher! Do as I say!
I’m not done talking to you!
Hold on, dammit!
Like I told you ordinary chains
are pointless!
They’re inferior!
And conjuring
some kind of unbreakable chain
is completely impossible!
[Kurapika] On September 1st,
Yorknew City will host
the world’s greatest auction.
That’s where the spider…
the Phantom Troupe will appear.
[chains jangling]
Huh?
That heartbeat…
It plays a horrible melody of rage…
So, you want me to find you an employer
with connections to the Yorknew auction?
Did I get that right?
That’s right.
Like the last guy who walked in.
Huh?
Same request twice today.
Amusing, is all.
The boy I just passed?
[Rei] Do you know him?
No, I don’t.
He’s interested in the auction, too?
But then…
why is his heartbeat so full of rage?
RITZ-CARLTON HOTEL
[cringing]
[thug 1] Eating with a twerp like that’ll
only make your food taste worse.
[thug 2]
Why don’t you let us take you out instead?
We’ll show you
the best night of your life, sweetheart.
This isn’t a date, unfortunately.
I’m in the middle of a job.
A job? Really?
-[man cringing]
-This is actually my employer.
He’s hired me as his bodyguard.
[thug 1] Bodyguard?
[thug 2] You’ve gotta be joking.
A babe like you… a bodyguard?
[all thugs laughing]
I’d be happy to let you guard my body…
I don't guard ugly men.
But thanks anyway.
Who do you think you’re talkin’ to?
Shut your--
[pervy cackle]
[woman] Instant Lover.
180-MINUTE LOVE SLAVE
INSTANT LOVER
Every single person that I kiss
becomes my willing slave.
[panting]
What’s your command, mistress?
I live to serve you!
Beat them up for me.
Yes, ma’am! My pleasure!
[all three thugs] Huh?
[gleeful laughter]
[punches and grunting]
[frightened squeak]
[screaming in terror]
[tires screeching]
[annoyed grunt] He ran away.
Ah, well.
Guess I’ll need another employer.
What a pain…
A splendid moon…
[guard 1] There he is!
[guard 2] We’ve got you now!
[guard 3] Hand over the corpse samples
you stole, nice and easy!
[derisive snort]
Don’t interrupt.
Not my work and not this splendid moon.
[annoyed growl]
That’s enough! Put your hands up!
[Basho] I was on the verge
of another masterful poem.
But you spoiled the moment, you imbeciles!
“Splendid full moon
and pursuers as clumsy as a baboon…”
[grunts] That sucks.
[birds chirping]
[Squala] Yes, I know, Eliza.
Well, if this job works out…
Yeah. There’s nothing to worry about.
I’ll handle it.
Right. I’ll take care of you and the dogs.
Really won’t be a problem.
So, don’t worry, Eliza.
Bear with me a little while longer.
Yeah. It’ll be fine.
You can count on me.
[doorbell sounds]
[Kurapika]
I was sent by the employment agency.
My name is Kurapika.
[dogs growling]
Welcome.
We’re happy that you could join us.
If you’d be so kind as to wait here.
[butler] Thank you for your patience.
It seems everyone has arrived,
so we will now begin
going over the details of the contract.
I’ll start by going over the requirements.
I won’t ask whether or not
you have a License.
My only concern
is whether you can obtain
the items we seek.
The auction, as you all know,
will begin in one month.
Before that time,
find one item from the list provided
and then bring it safely back here.
Here you go.
These are the data cards you’re assigned.
LOCK OF HAIR FROM THE FAMOUS ACTRESS, SARA
A RIGHT ARM OF A MUMMY
FROM AN EGYPTIAN TOMB
THE SCALY SKIN OF A PATIENT
WITH ICHTHYOSIS
THE SKULL OF A ONE-HORNED CREATURE
[gasps]
THE EYEBALLS OF A KURTA.
[seething]
What?
Something wrong?
You look a little pale.
Ah. The eyeballs of a Kurta, huh?
“Difficulty Level: A.
Preserve the post-mortem scarlet hue
after death.
Complete set with head preferred."
Yeah, I’ve heard about that.
Their eyes turn red
whenever they’re excited.
-You see, the Kurta--
-Shut up.
That’s enough.
[derisive snort]
I'll say it again:
All that’s required is one item
from the list you’ve been given.
If you are successful,
you’ll be hired
and begin your training
in security and acquisitions.
Well, then. Best of luck to you.
[Kurapika] I will pass this test.
First, I must ingratiate myself
and win their trust.
In all likelihood, the man we saw
was not the actual client,
thus, illustrating the distance
between the client and myself.
It’s critical that I get
as close to them as possible
until they eventually let their guard down
and share their secrets.
There are two things
that collectors always desire.
The first is any item of extreme rarity.
The second is colleagues to whom
they can brag about their collection.
He must have connections
to other flesh collectors...
those who share
their disgusting acquisitions,
a network of scum.
I will infiltrate their ranks
and eradicate them all.
[mustached man] Hey… It won’t open.
[man on screen]
I forgot to mention one thing:
the minimum requirement for the position
is strength.
Enough strength
to get out of this mansion...
with your lives.
[narrator] Kurapika pursues his quest
to avenge his brethren
and punish the Phantom Troupe.
And right now,
he is preparing
to enter a new battlefield.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Coming up:
-Gon...
-[Killua] ...and Killua’s…
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I’m Gon!
-I’m Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today we’re introducing Mizuken,
Kurapika’s teacher!
And he’s an Emitter type.
I guess Nen users are fated
to meet Nen teachers.
It happened to us.
[both] Maybe that’s why we met each other.
It’s fate!
[Gon] Next Time: "Nen x Users x Unite"?
[Killua] Hey, Gon…
Let's go break
some of Milluki's figurines!
[Gon] Count me in as your accomplice!